L. Patrick Gray III Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Alphabetical File, 1936-2008 (Box 70-101)
  - Health, Education, and Welfare Department, 1969-1970, (2 folders) (Box 77)
  - Honors, awards, and credentials, 1949-1958, 1968-1982, 2006 See also Oversize (Box 77)
  - Honors, awards, and credentials, image files, 2006, mss86267_175_002
  - Intelligence, general, 1977-1981 (Box 77)
  - Intelligence activities, congressional oversight, 1975-1977 (Box 77)
  - Justice Department (Box 77)
    - Civil Division (Box 77)
      - Executive privilege, 1971-1972 (Box 77)
      - Freedom of the press, 1970-1972 (Box 77)
      - International Telephone and Telegraph Corp. (ITT), 1971-1972, (3 folders) (Box 77)
      - Letter to the editor, 1972 (Box 78)
      - Life magazine article, 1972 (Box 78)
      - Miscellany, 1970-1972 (Box 78)
      - Richardson v. Wright, 1971-1972 (Box 78)
      - Rosenbaum, Francis N., Andrew L. Stone, and Chromcraft Corp., 1970-1972, (2 folders) (Box 78)
      - Sparrow v. Goodman, 1971-1972, (2 folders) (Box 78)
      - Speaking engagements (Box 78)
        - 1971 (Box 78)
        - 1972, (7 folders) (Box 79)
      - Telephone calls, 1971-1972 (Box 80)
    - Kleindienst, Richard G., hearings, 1972-1973 (Box 80)
    - Nomination, deputy attorney general, 1972 (Box 80)
    - Personnel file, 1970-1972 (Box 80)
  - Legal practice (Box 80)
    - Alphabetical file, 1981-1984, (8 folders) (Box 80)
    - Partnership at Suisman, Shapiro, Wool, Brennan, and Gray, New London, Conn., 1967 (Box 81)
    - Weekly planner, 1980-1982, (3 folders) (Box 81)
  - Military papers (Box 81)
    - Legal file, 1950-1954, (2 folders) (Box 81)
    - Miscellany, 1936, 1943-1960 (Box 81)
    - Orders, 1940-1958, (2 folders) (Box 81)
    - Personal file, 1945-1960 See also Classified, (10 folders) (Box 82)
    - Personal file, 1945-1960, (13 folders) (Box 83)
    - Personal file, 1945-1960, (12 folders) (Box 84)
    - Personal file, 1945-1960, (3 folders) (Box 85)
    - Retirement, 1951-1967, (2 folders) (Box 85)
    - Study report, 1958 See also Classified (Box 85)
  - Nameplates, undated (Box 85)
  - Nixon, Richard M. (Box 85)
    - Inauguration, 1969, 1973, (2 folders) (Box 85)
    - Miscellany, 1966-1978 (Box 85)
    - Position in administration, 1965-1969 (Box 85)
    - Presidential campaign (Box 85)
      - 1961 (Box 85)
      - 1966-1969, (4 folders) (Box 86)
    - White House tapes (Box 86)
      - Annotated excerpts, 1974-1978, 2006, (2 folders) (Box 86)
      - Richard M. Nixon, John Ehrlichman, and L. Patrick Gary III, 16 Feb. 1973, transcript, 1973 (Box 86)
  - Notes and jottings, 1976-2005, undated (Box 86)
  - Pat Gray Legal Defense Fund (Box 86)
    - Contribution thank you letters (Box 86)
      - 1978, (2 folders) (Box 86)
      - 1978, (5 folders) (Box 87)
      - 1979-1980, (3 folders) (Box 87)
    - Contributions (Box 88)
      - 1978-1980, (2 folders) (Box 88)
      - circa 1978-circa 1980, (2 folders) (Box 88)
      - circa 1978-circa 1980, (1 folder) (Box 89)
    - Correspondence and telephone calls (Box 89)
      - Hoker, Joseph E., 1978-1979, (4 folders) (Box 89)
      - Miscellaneous, 1978, 2006 (Box 89)
      - Nelson, O. B., 1978-1982, (4 folders) (Box 90)
      - Special Agents Legal Fund, 1978-1981, (3 folders) (Box 90)
      - Special Agents Legal Fund, 1878-1981, (1 folder) (Box 91)
      - Whitaker, John C., 1978-1980 (Box 91)
      - Winters, Leigh, 1978-1980 (Box 91)
    - Ledger, 1978-1982 (Box 91)
    - Letters to editors, 1978, (2 folders) (Box 91)
    - Memoranda to the committee (Box 91)
      - 1978-1979, (3 folders) (Box 91)
      - 1980-1981, (3 folders) (Box 92)
    - Miscellany, 1978-1982 (Box 92)
    - Steering group chairman, outgoing communications (Box 92)
      - 1978-1981, (3 folders) (Box 92)
    - Tax protest, 1978-1981, (3 folders) (Box 92)
    - Tax protest, 1978-1981, (3 folders) (Box 93)
    - United States Naval Academy, class of 1940, 1978-1979, (2 folders) (Box 93)
  - Personal papers, lists and notes, 1979-2008, (2 folders) (Box 93)
  - Personal papers, lists, image files, 2006, mss86267_175_032
  - Photographs (Box 94)
    - Federal Bureau of Investigation, 1972-1973 See also Oversize, (6 folders) (Box 94)
    - Health, Education, and Welfare Department, 1969-1970, (2 folders) (Box 95)
    - Justice Department, 1970-1972 See also Oversize (Box 95)
    - Miscellaneous, 1971-1972, undated (Box 95)
    - Nixon, Richard M., circa 1960, 1969-1972 See also Oversize (Box 95)
    - Portraits, 1950s-1970s See also Oversize, (2 folders) (Box 95)
    - United States Navy, circa 1940-1950s, undated See also Oversize (Box 95)
  - Press clippings (Box 96)
    - 1938, 1943, 1952, 1961-1972, (8 folders) (Box 96)
    - 1973, (1 folder) (Box 96)
    - 1973, (1 folder) (Box 97)
    - 1974-2005, undated, (7 folders) (Box 97)
  - Press problems, 1973-1983, 1996, 2005, (3 folders) (Box 97)
  - Scrapbook, 1968-1971 See Oversize (Box 97)
  - Scrapbook material, 1960-1973, (1 folder) (Box 97)
  - Scrapbook material, 1960-1973 See also Oversize, (5 folders) (Box 98)
  - Telephone log, 2001-2003 (Box 98)
  - Television interviews, 1980, 2005, (2 folders) (Box 98)
  - Television interview, video, letter, image files, 2005, mss86267_175_001; mss86267_175_014
  - United States Naval Academy, class of 1940, 1980-1982, 2000, (2 folders) (Box 99)
  - Watergate Affair, printed matter, 1973-1982, (4 folders) (Box 99)
  - Weatherman (organization), 1977-1981 (Box 99)
  - Writings by others (Box 99)
    - DeLoach, Cartha, book inscription, 1995 (Box 99)
    - Felt, W. Mark, The FBI Pyramid from the Inside, 1979-1980 (Box 99)
    - Hartline, Donald, "The Tenure of Louis Patrick Gray III as the Acting Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation," research project, Heidelberg College, Tiffin, Ohio, 1973-1974 (Box 100)
    - Notes on other books, 1980, circa 2001-circa 2003 (Box 100)
    - Powers, Thomas, The Man Who Kept the Secrets: Richard Helms and the CIA, 1979 (Box 100)
    - Purvis, Joseph D., The Era of J. Edgar, 1995-1998 (Box 101)
    - Sullivan, William C., with Bill Brown, The Bureau: My Thirty Years in Hoover's FBI, 1979 (Box 101)
- Closed, 1973-1977 (Box X102)
  The Closed series contains transcripts and notes about grand jury testimony pertaining to the Watergate Affair and the methods used to locate Weatherman fugitives while Gray was acting director of the FBI.
  Arranged according to the series, containers, and folders from which the items were separated.
  - Legal File (Box X102)
    - United States v. Gray
      - Federal grand jury, 1976-1977 (Container 27) (Box X102)
    - Watergate Affair
      - Federal grand jury, 1973 (Container 48), (2 folders) (Box X102)
      - Federal grand jury, 1974 (Container 48) (Box X102)
  - Speeches and Writings (Box X102)
    - Book project
      - Resource material
        - Numerical file
          - 19. Watergate grand jury July 19-20, 1973, 1973 (Container 62) (Box X102)
- Classified, 1946-1981 (Box CL 1-CL 2)
  Correspondence, memoranda, notes, and hearing transcripts pertaining to the work of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and testimony before the House Committee on Armed Services Special Subcommittee on Intelligence and a Senate Committee on Appropriations subcommittee regarding aspects of the investigation of the Watergate Affair.
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation (Box CL 1)
    - Al Fatah (organization), 1979 (Container 6) (Box CL 1)
  - Legal File (Box CL 1)
    - United States v. Gray
      - Discovery documents, 1969-1975 (Containers 25-26) (Box CL 1)
      - Federal grand jury, 1976-1978 (Container 27) (Box CL 1)
      - Interviews, 1979 (Container 28) (Box CL 1)
      - Motions, memoranda, and related material, 1979 (Container 30) (Box CL 1)
      - Notes
        - Miscellaneous, 1978-1981 (Container 32) (Box CL 1)
      - Summaries for lawyer, 1976 (Container 34) (Box CL 1)
    - Watergate Affair
      - Congress
        - House Committee on Armed Services Special Subcommittee on Intelligence (Nedzi Committee), 1972 (Container 37) (Box CL 2)
        - Senate Committee on Appropriations Subcommittee (McClellan Committee), 1973 (Container 38) (Box CL 2)
      - Watergate Special Prosecution Force
        - Documents
          - Sent to lawyer, 1972 (Container 48) (Box CL 2)
        - Wiretap investigation
          - Lawyer's file, undated (Container 52) (Box CL 2)
  - Alphabetical File (Box CL 2)
    - Military papers
      - Personal file, 1946 (Container 82) (Box CL 2)
      - Study report, 1958 (Container 85) (Box CL 2)
- Oversize, 1949-1973 (Box OV 1-OV 3)
  Certificates, photographs, a scrapbook documenting Gray's experience as executive assistant to the secretary of the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare and as assistant attorney general for the Civil Division at the Department of Justice, and a bumper sticker from that period.
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation (Box OV 1)
    - Nomination
      - Congratulatory letters
        - W, 1973 (Container 13) (Box OV 1)
  - Alphabetical File (Box OV 1)
    - Honors, awards, and credentials, 1949-1972 (Container 77) (Box OV 1)
    - Photographs (Box OV 2)
      - Federal Bureau of Investigation, 1972 (Container 94) (Box OV 2)
      - Justice Department, circa 1972 (Container 95) (Box OV 2)
      - Nixon, Richard M., circa 1960-1972 (Container 95) (Box OV 2)
      - Portraits, undated (Container 95) (Box OV 2)
      - United States Navy, undated (Container 95) (Box OV 2)
    - Scrapbook, 1968-1971 (Container 97) (Box OV 3)
    - Scrapbook material, circa 1971 (Container 98) (Box OV 3)